# Ângelo Ocanã Martins

Address: Ottawa, ON E-mail: <a href="mailto:angeloocana@gmail.com">angeloocana@gmail.com</a>

Phone: (613) 720-9572 Site: angeloocana.com

Github: github.com/angeloocana Pluralsight: pluralsight.com/profile/ocanaangelo

## Objective

Senior Javascript Full-stack Developer (Nodejs, React, GraphQL, MongoDB, and Docker).

#### About Me

My professional journey started when I was 14 years-old. Since then, I have been passionate about programming. Most recently, I have my mind set on TDD (Test Driven Development), Functional Programming, Offline First, Mobile First, and Frog Cloud.

## Work Experience

2007 - Present Freelancer **Senior Full-stack Developer** | Latest Projects:

budbuds.us

Coding | React Native, Redux, Graphql, Nodejs, Postgres, Redis and Docker.

• <u>tic-tac-toe-ai.surge.sh</u>

Design and Coding | Html Canvas, React, Jest, Graphql, Nodejs, and Gatsby.

angeloocana.com

Design and Coding | React, Jest, Graphql, Nodejs, and Gatsby.

• <u>github.com/polutz/polutz</u>

Coding | React, Mocha, Graphql, Nodejs, TypeScript, and Docker.

novoterritorio.azurewebsites.net

Coding | D3, Angular, Ionic, TypeScript, Jasmine, C#, MongoDB, Azure, SASS, and Gulp.

staffgeist.com

Coding | Angular, Ionic, TypeScript, Jasmine, C#, MongoDB, Elasticsearch, Azure, SASS, and Gulp.

• <u>jumpoverjump.com</u>

Design and Coding | Angular, Ionic, Jasmine, C#, MongoDB, Azure, SASS, and Gulp.

2011 - 2015 POL, Peela, Total On Demand

#### Lead Senior C# Software Developer

- Developed web platform for Small-Medium marketing and endomarketing campaigns, 5-8 projects every year. 5K-9Million Users.
- Created their own e-commerce platform.
- Provided consultations to extract clients needs and develop strategies.

Technologies: Javascript, C#, .net MVC, Structuremap, Web Forms, JQuery, SQL Server, Postgres, DDD, TDD, Lucene, Elasticsearch, RabbitMQ, Heroku and Amazon AWS.

Clients: Loreal, Johnson, Sony, Vivo|Telefonica, Volkswagen, Walmart, BASF, Net, FMC, FTD, Sky, OI, BRF, Syngenta, Cury, Tenda, B2W, Magazine Luiza, FastShop, ...et al.

#### 2010 -2011 Empresário Cobrança

#### Lead C# Software Developer

- Developed web platform to manage debt collection.
- Worked with complex mathematical algorithms to calculate interest rates.
- Created company's own barcode generation software.
- Development of internal Human Resources systems.
- Building access control system using webcams.
- Developed an internal financial control system.
- Wrote performative queries to work with a 500GB SQL Server database over millions of rows.

Technologies: Javascript, C#, WCF, WPF, WebForms, Windows Forms, Windows Services, EXT.Net, Jquery, and SQL Server.

#### 2010 -2010 Media W

#### C# Software Developer

Developed POS Desktop Terminal following government regulations.

Technologies: C#, Windows Forms, and MySQL

#### 2008 - 2010 Upgrade Consultoria

### Junior C# Software Developer

- PriManager Developing web platform to manage large-scale construction environments.
- FDE Web platform for managing public schools in São Paulo/BR.
- Developed their own ERP & CRM.

Technologies: Javascript, C#, Webforms, Telerik, JQuery, Web Services, Windows Services, Flash, Action Script, and SQL Server.

#### Education

2012 - Present Pluralsight

Design and Technology

pluralsight.com/profile/ocanaangelo

2013 - 2014 UNIP - Universidade Paulista

Analysis and System Development

2011 - 2010 FIAP - Faculdade de Informática e Administração Paulista

Analysis and System Development

2007 - 2009 FIEE

Web Design with Emphasis on Digital Media

## Languages

English	Portuguese	French	Spanish
Fluent	Native	Basic	Proficient